

## Teija Alasalmi - CV

Email: teija.alasalmi@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://github.com/in/teija-alasalmi">www.linkedin.com/in/teija-alasalmi</a>
Github: <a href="https://github.com/teijatestaaja/">https://github.com/teijatestaaja/</a>

I am a strong testing and test automation professional and an excellent team player. I have been working in software development in various roles since 2005. I have experience in the following industries: pension insurance, financial systems, public administration (Tax, Customs), education, translation, software localization, mobile networks and mobile games. I am fluent in Robot Framework, Python, JavaScript, Java and Kotlin. I enjoy new challenges both at work and in my spare time. My descriptive personality traits include perseverance, curiosity and willingness to experiment. I am a quick learner and I enjoy working in a team to achieve common goals for enabling customers' success.

### Work Experience

**Test Automation Specialist** 

10/2021 -

Tieto Finland Oy, Helsinki

**Test Automation Developer** 

4/2021 - 9/2021

Gofore, Helsinki

**Senior Test Automation Specialist /** 

Test Manager

1/2020 - 3/2021

CGI, Helsinki

Test Automation Specialist /

**Test Manager / Test Consultant /** 

**Test Engineer** 

6/2010 - 12/2019

Digia, Helsinki

**Software Analyst** 

9/2008 – 5/2010

University of Jyväskylä

**Mobile Game Tester** 

10/2005 - 8/2007

Digital Chocolate Inc., Helsinki

**Project Coordinator** 

6/2005 - 9/2005

Suomen kieltenopettajien liitto, Helsinki

**English Teacher** 

1/2005 - 6/2005

Lauttasaari Primary School, City of

Helsinki

### Education

**Master of Science** 

2020

Computer Science, Mathematics

University of Jyväskylä

**Bachelor of Business IT** 

2021

Computer Programming

Haaga-Helia University of Applied

**Sciences** 

**Master of Arts** 

2014

English, Intercultural Studies

University of Jyväskylä

**Bachelor of Science** 

2013

Computer Science, Pedagogical Studies for

Teachers, University of Jyväskylä

#### **Bachelor of Arts**

2011

English, Spanish, Language Technology

University of Jyväskylä

#### Finnish Matriculation Examination

1998

Specialized in Art, Mathematics and

Languages

Linnan lukio, Kajaani

### Certifications

Scrum Master	ISTQB Test	<b>ISTQB</b> Certified	Language
Scrum Alliance	Manager	Tester	Certificate
2/2019	Advanced Level	Foundation Level	Spanish,
	9/2017	9/2013	Intermediate level

11/2011

## Core Testing & Programming Skills

Test automation	Manual testing	Python (excellent)	C++, C (good)
Test planning	Acceptance testing	JavaScript (good)	HTML5 (good)
Test management	TDD, ATDD	Java (good)	XML (good)
Functional testing	Exploratory testing	Kotlin (good)	CSS (good)
Test case creation	API testing	React (good)	SQL, R (good)

# Knowledge of Testing Tools, IDEs & Operating Systems

Azure DevOps	Robot Framework	Xcode	Android Studio
JIRA & Xray, Zephyr	Selenium + IDE	Visual Studio Code	Gimp
Quality Center	Detox	Eclipse	Photoshop
TestRail	Jest & Mocha	Visual Studio	Office Tools
TFS	SoapUI	Git, GitHub	Windows
Test Track Pro	OWASP ZAP	GitLab + Bitbucket	Mac OS, iOS
SpriraTest	DbVisualizer	Sublime Text	Linux basics
Bugzilla	SQLiteStudio	Postman	Android basics

### Language Skills

Finnish (native) French (basics) English (working knowledge) Italian (basics) Spanish (working knowledge) Portuguese (basics)

Portuguese, Swedish (intermediate) German, Japanese (very basics)

### **Hobbies**

Rugby (Finland women's national rugby team 2008-2021, club rugby since 2008) Crocheting & knitting

Shotokan karate (brown belt) Taekwondo (yellow belt)

Weight training

Coding & learning languages

Video & mobile games, board games